The Return of the King is a animation, fantasy,
adventure film directed by Jules Bass.
Two Hobbits struggle to destroy the Ring in Mount Doom while their friends
desperately fight evil Lord Sauron's forces in a final battle.
Frodo Baggins / Bilbo Baggins (voice), played by Orson Bean.
Samwise Gamgee (voice), played by Roddy McDowall.
Gandalf (voice), played by John Huston.
Gollum (voice), played by Theodore Gottlieb.
Meriadoc 'Merry' Brandybuck (voice), played by Casey Kasem.
Peregrin 'Pippin' Took (voice), played by Sonny Melendrez.
The Return of the King (also known as The Return of the King: A Story of the
Hobbits) is a 1980 animated musical fantasy television film.
It is a sequel to The Hobbit (1977).
The film is an adaptation of The Return of the King, the third and
final volume of the 1955 novel The Lord of the Rings by J.
The first two parts of Tolkien's story, The Fellowship of the Ring and The Two Towers, are not
covered in this release and are only briefly summarized at the beginning of the movie.
The special aired on ABC on Sunday, May 11, 1980.
Both critics and fans gave The Return of the King an indifferent reception.
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, elves, shire, musical, tower.